# TIANYIN ZHANG

San Jose, CA | tianyinzhang.com | (408)609-4697 | tianyinzhang1999@gmail.com

### **SUMMARY**

A creative and forward-thinking Computer Science graduate who enjoys software development as well as learning new technology. Experienced software developer, team contributor, and analytical problem-solver with strong learning capability and communication skills. Specifically aims to solve ambiguous problems with practical solutions.

#### **EDUCATION**

## New York University, New York, NY

September 2019 - May 2023

College of Arts and Science, Bachelor of Arts in Computer Science

- Overall GPA: 3.49
- Minor in Web Programming & Applications

#### **CERTIFICATION**

• Learning Full-Stack JavaScript Development: MongoDB, Node, and React – LinkedIn Learning

#### **SKILLS**

- Programming Language: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Python, SQL
- Tools: Figma, MongoDB, Firebase, ExpressJS, ReactJS, TailwindCSS, NodeJS, Bootstrap, Git
- Agile Methodology, Scrum Framework.
- Time and Tasks Management, Organization and Coordination, Collaborative working, remote collaboration.
- Hobbies: Personal Electric Vehicle, Photography, Videography.

## PROJECT EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer, Open EDU (School Project), New York, NY

January 2023 - May 2023

- Designed, developed, and deployed a mobile web app using **ReactJS**, **ExpressJS**, **NodeJS**, **and MongoDB**.
- Utilized Figma to design an intuitive user interface, resulting in a 50% decrease in user navigation time and an increase in overall user satisfaction by 20%.
- Led development process under the Agile methodology and Scrum Framework.
- Partnered with 4 other teammates in designing, coding, troubleshooting, debugging, and deployment.

Full Stack Developer, Plant Your Dreams (School Project), New York, NY

September 2022 - December 2022

- Developed a multi-page web app using JavaScript, React.JS, Firebase, HTML, and CSS.
- Managed both back-end and front-end aspects of the development process.
- Implemented **ReactJS** component, increased overall user satisfaction by 30%.
- Led sessions for code review, version-control duties, debugging, and refactoring code base.
- Collaborated with 3 teammates under agile methodology and served the team as Scrum Master.

## **COMMUNITY WORK**

Founder, PEV NYC, New York, NY

October 2021 - Present

- Founded, and administered a local non-profit PEV hobbyist group with healthy growth.
- Attracted more than **190 active members**.
- Hosting, and supervising weekly in-person events, and online discussion chats.
- Providing a platform for local enthusiasts to communicate knowledge and trade parts.
- Engage sponsors and coordinate events for relative businesses in the industry: local small businesses, and international manufacturers.